In my previous show, we learned that containerization technology helps software run easily, freely and independently, but how to put software in a container
How to run the container
To answer those questions, let's meet the hero behind the scene, Tucker, a container runtime, and its processes
What is Tucker? What is container runtime? What are the processes? It sounds complicated
No worries, let's simply watch a short story
This is Docke
Docke works on a Docke
He packs and loads cargo sunbessels
He helps his clients to ship stuff all over the world
It is an important job
Docke likes his job
One day a client named Jane comes to the Docke
Jane urgently needs to ship many different packages
How to do that quickly? Docke gets a shipping instruction list
It lists everything on how to ship Jane's stuff in a container, what type of container, how to upload her stuff to the container, and how to ship the container on the boat, etc
This is just like software containerization
First, a container runtime, such as Docker, needs to be available on the server
Next, a Docker file is prepared with all the steps to pack the software to the container and to run the container on the server
Following the instructions, Docke works diligently on building Jane's container
This is exactly what the software Docker is doing, building the container following the Docker file instructions
When the container is done, Docke sticks a label on it and pushes it to the container warehouse, waiting for the next shipping time
As for the software Docker, the finished container is called container image, just like a container template
Similarly, Docker tags and pushes the image to the image registry, the warehouse
It is time to ship
Docke pulls the container out of the warehouse and uploads it to the boat
Now Jane's stuff is ready to go to the world
At the same time, the software Docker pulls out the image, runs container instances on the server, to serve the world
Congratulations! Now you understand Docker, the container runtime, and its processes, simple
In the real shipping world, things can be more complicated on a large scale
With so many containers and operations, orchestration is needed
It is the same in the software world
Do you know who is the best container orchestrator? Comment it below
Keep learning
No matter how complex it seems, remember, it is just a docking and shipping business, simple.